<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     >

  <channel>
    <title>Composing with Process. Perspectives on Generative and Systems Music</title>
    <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/taxonomy_serie_podcast/composing-with-process/</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Mark Fell, Joe Gilmore and MACBA</copyright>
    <description>Curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore. Narrated by Connie Treanor. Each episode of this  series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two pieces by Goodiepal or Gæoudjiparl van den Dobbelsteen, whose real name is Parl Kristian Bjørn Vester.</description>

    <item>
      <title>#9.1. Two Discrete Generative Systems</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-9-1-two-discrete-generative-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore wrap up this series on generative and process music with a piece created specifically for the occasion: 'Two Discrete Generative Systems'.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The focus of the ninth episode in this series is a project entitled ‘Two Discrete Generative Systems’ by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</p>
      <p>The works referred to in the title were developed separately and first heard together at Enjoy ArtSpace, Leeds, UK, on 29 April 2013. The recording presented here is an ambisonic room recording of the event which was open to the public. It is hoped that the works and their combination respond to some of the key themes addressed throughout the series.</p>
      <p>Gilmore’s piece, presented on four loudspeakers, explores behaviours generated by a flocking algorithm. These behaviours are used to control the frequency and amplitude of four oscillators. The piece is presented as a series of ‘studies’ of fixed duration followed by one minute of silence.</p>
      <p>In each study the conditions of the flock are predetermined. Flocking is a description of the group bahaviour of living things such as birds, fish and bacteria. In flock simulations, the motion of each agent is dependent on the conditions governing the overall behaviour of the flock, and also on the interaction between autonomous agents.</p>
      <p>The three main conditions governing movement are avoidance, alignment, and coherence. Although flocking exhibits somewhat chaotic motion, in reality there is a complex set of behavioural interaction occuring between individuals in the flock.</p>
      <p>While Gilmore’s piece explores tonality with multiple loudspeakers, Fell’s contribution by contrast uses a single speaker, centrally placed, playing rhythmic structures with a percussive single sound principally derived from the Linn kick drum. Among the arrangement of speakers a computer is placed on a plinth, this displays a collection of sliders that are used to generate and change the rhythm that is played.</p>
      <p>Audience members take it in turns to change the sliders and make patterns. The algorithm used to produce to rhythmic structures is based around groupings of durations and repetitions of temporal intervals. This simple structure generates a number of distinct patterns.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_09_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#8.1. Models of Change</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-8-1-models-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode considers the notion of change in music. It looks at how scientific and mathematical concepts can be used to model change in the acoustic domain.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Episode eight in the series continues to look at how composers working with generative systems implement change in their works. This episode focuses on models of change using mathematical structures derived from complex dynamic systems observed in nature.</p>
      <p>Through advances in mathematics, physics and biology, the programme looks at how composers have utilised the central findings of chaos theory and emergent systems – such as cellular automata, Lindenmeyer Systems and fractal geometry – to generate automated dynamic patterns of change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_08_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#8.1. Models of Change</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-8-1-models-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #8.1.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The eight episode in COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC continues to look at how composers working with generative systems implement change in their works. This episode focuses on models of change using mathematical structures derived from complex dynamic systems observed in nature.</p>
      <p>Through advances in mathematics, physics and biology, the programme looks at how composers have utilised the central findings of chaos theory and emergent systems — such as cellular automata, Lindenmeyer Systems and fractal geometry — to generate automated dynamic patterns of change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess8_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#7.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-7-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Two exclusive works-interviews by Goodiepal.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Each episode of this  series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two pieces by Goodiepal or Gæoudjiparl van den Dobbelsteen, whose real name is Parl Kristian Bjørn Vester.]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_07_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#7.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-7-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #7.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The seventh episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC looks at how several notable composers working with generative systems conceive of, control and implement change in their works. Change plays a central role in music.</p>
      <p>Music develops into different phases, has a temporal structure of one sort or another, even a sustained waveform changes in some respect throughout its duration. Based upon interviews and drawing from previously unpublished materials the show examines notions of repetition, anticipation and predictability, the interplay of change at distinct altitudes within the work, and the role of automation and human agency to invoke change.<p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess7_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#7.1 Approaches to change</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-7-1-approaches-to-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode considers the notion of change in music. It asks how we perceive and quantify change in musical structures, and how generative processes disrupt and enlarge our sense of surprise, expectation, tension and boredom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The seventh episode in the series looks at how several notable composers working with generative systems conceive of, control and implement change in their works. Change plays a central role in music.</p>
      <p>Music develops into different phases, has a temporal structure of one sort or another, even a sustained waveform changes in some respect throughout its duration. Based upon interviews and drawing from previously unpublished materials the show examines notions of repetition, anticipation and predictability, the interplay of change at distinct altitudes within the work, and the role of automation and human agency to invoke change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_07_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#6.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-6-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by Stephan Mathieu and Russell Haswell.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Each episode of this series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two process-led works by German composer Stephan Mathieu and British multidisciplinary artist Russell Haswell.]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_06_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#6.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-6-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #6.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sixth episode of  COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC considers the relationship between process-based music and space. It explores how musicians and composers have used acoustic space as an active element in music composition. Some historical precedents, such as Tibetan and medieval chanting, are included; acoustic space has not only been explored externally, but also internally, as physiological space.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess6_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#6.1 Space</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-6-1-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode explores sound in relation to space. It considers various ways in which composers have utilised acoustic space as an active element in the process of music composition.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sixth episode in the series considers the relationship between process-based music and space. It explores how musicians and composers have used acoustic space as an active element in music composition.</p>
<p>Some historical precedents, such as Tibetan and medieval chanting, are included; acoustic space has not only been explored externally, but also internally, as physiological space.</p>
<p>We look at several examples of music which explore these principles, including: Austrian composer Peter Ablinger’s exploration of acoustic space using silence and noise; and Italian composer Agostino di Scipio’s ‘Audible Eco-Systems’ which explore the real-time interaction between digital signal processing (DSP) and the space in which it is located.</p>
<p>The show closes with two performative works which differ in their approach: ‘495, 63’ by Yasunao Tone and Carl Michael von Hausswolff’s freq_out project.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_06_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>
