<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     >

  <channel>
    <title>Composing with Process. Perspectives on Generative and Systems Music</title>
    <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/taxonomy_serie_podcast/composing-with-process/</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Mark Fell, Joe Gilmore and MACBA</copyright>
    <description>Curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore. Narrated by Connie Treanor. Each episode of this  series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two pieces by Goodiepal or Gæoudjiparl van den Dobbelsteen, whose real name is Parl Kristian Bjørn Vester.</description>

    <item>
      <title>#9.1. Two Discrete Generative Systems</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-9-1-two-discrete-generative-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore wrap up this series on generative and process music with a piece created specifically for the occasion: 'Two Discrete Generative Systems'.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The focus of the ninth episode in this series is a project entitled ‘Two Discrete Generative Systems’ by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</p>
      <p>The works referred to in the title were developed separately and first heard together at Enjoy ArtSpace, Leeds, UK, on 29 April 2013. The recording presented here is an ambisonic room recording of the event which was open to the public. It is hoped that the works and their combination respond to some of the key themes addressed throughout the series.</p>
      <p>Gilmore’s piece, presented on four loudspeakers, explores behaviours generated by a flocking algorithm. These behaviours are used to control the frequency and amplitude of four oscillators. The piece is presented as a series of ‘studies’ of fixed duration followed by one minute of silence.</p>
      <p>In each study the conditions of the flock are predetermined. Flocking is a description of the group bahaviour of living things such as birds, fish and bacteria. In flock simulations, the motion of each agent is dependent on the conditions governing the overall behaviour of the flock, and also on the interaction between autonomous agents.</p>
      <p>The three main conditions governing movement are avoidance, alignment, and coherence. Although flocking exhibits somewhat chaotic motion, in reality there is a complex set of behavioural interaction occuring between individuals in the flock.</p>
      <p>While Gilmore’s piece explores tonality with multiple loudspeakers, Fell’s contribution by contrast uses a single speaker, centrally placed, playing rhythmic structures with a percussive single sound principally derived from the Linn kick drum. Among the arrangement of speakers a computer is placed on a plinth, this displays a collection of sliders that are used to generate and change the rhythm that is played.</p>
      <p>Audience members take it in turns to change the sliders and make patterns. The algorithm used to produce to rhythmic structures is based around groupings of durations and repetitions of temporal intervals. This simple structure generates a number of distinct patterns.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_09_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#8.1. Models of Change</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-8-1-models-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode considers the notion of change in music. It looks at how scientific and mathematical concepts can be used to model change in the acoustic domain.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Episode eight in the series continues to look at how composers working with generative systems implement change in their works. This episode focuses on models of change using mathematical structures derived from complex dynamic systems observed in nature.</p>
      <p>Through advances in mathematics, physics and biology, the programme looks at how composers have utilised the central findings of chaos theory and emergent systems – such as cellular automata, Lindenmeyer Systems and fractal geometry – to generate automated dynamic patterns of change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_08_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#8.1. Models of Change</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-8-1-models-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #8.1.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The eight episode in COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC continues to look at how composers working with generative systems implement change in their works. This episode focuses on models of change using mathematical structures derived from complex dynamic systems observed in nature.</p>
      <p>Through advances in mathematics, physics and biology, the programme looks at how composers have utilised the central findings of chaos theory and emergent systems — such as cellular automata, Lindenmeyer Systems and fractal geometry — to generate automated dynamic patterns of change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess8_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#7.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-7-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Two exclusive works-interviews by Goodiepal.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Each episode of this  series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two pieces by Goodiepal or Gæoudjiparl van den Dobbelsteen, whose real name is Parl Kristian Bjørn Vester.]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_07_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#7.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-7-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #7.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The seventh episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC looks at how several notable composers working with generative systems conceive of, control and implement change in their works. Change plays a central role in music.</p>
      <p>Music develops into different phases, has a temporal structure of one sort or another, even a sustained waveform changes in some respect throughout its duration. Based upon interviews and drawing from previously unpublished materials the show examines notions of repetition, anticipation and predictability, the interplay of change at distinct altitudes within the work, and the role of automation and human agency to invoke change.<p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess7_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#7.1 Approaches to change</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-7-1-approaches-to-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode considers the notion of change in music. It asks how we perceive and quantify change in musical structures, and how generative processes disrupt and enlarge our sense of surprise, expectation, tension and boredom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The seventh episode in the series looks at how several notable composers working with generative systems conceive of, control and implement change in their works. Change plays a central role in music.</p>
      <p>Music develops into different phases, has a temporal structure of one sort or another, even a sustained waveform changes in some respect throughout its duration. Based upon interviews and drawing from previously unpublished materials the show examines notions of repetition, anticipation and predictability, the interplay of change at distinct altitudes within the work, and the role of automation and human agency to invoke change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_07_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#6.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-6-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by Stephan Mathieu and Russell Haswell.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Each episode of this series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two process-led works by German composer Stephan Mathieu and British multidisciplinary artist Russell Haswell.]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_06_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#6.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-6-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #6.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sixth episode of  COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC considers the relationship between process-based music and space. It explores how musicians and composers have used acoustic space as an active element in music composition. Some historical precedents, such as Tibetan and medieval chanting, are included; acoustic space has not only been explored externally, but also internally, as physiological space.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess6_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#6.1 Space</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-6-1-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode explores sound in relation to space. It considers various ways in which composers have utilised acoustic space as an active element in the process of music composition.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sixth episode in the series considers the relationship between process-based music and space. It explores how musicians and composers have used acoustic space as an active element in music composition.</p>
      <p>Some historical precedents, such as Tibetan and medieval chanting, are included; acoustic space has not only been explored externally, but also internally, as physiological space.</p>
      <p>We look at several examples of music which explore these principles, including: Austrian composer Peter Ablinger’s exploration of acoustic space using silence and noise; and Italian composer Agostino di Scipio’s ‘Audible Eco-Systems’ which explore the real-time interaction between digital signal processing (DSP) and the space in which it is located.</p>
      <p>The show closes with two performative works which differ in their approach: ‘495, 63’ by Yasunao Tone and Carl Michael von Hausswolff’s freq_out project.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_06_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#5.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-5-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by Ben Vida and THE HUB.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>Each episode of this series is followed by a special accompanying programme of exclusive music by leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This one presents two contrasting generative works by American composer Ben Vida and network group THE HUB.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_05_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#5.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-5-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #5.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The fifth episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC  continues to explore the idea of time in music practice, particularly in relation to duration.</p><p>The show looks at how music is measured in terms of both micro and macroscopic intervals: through granular synthesis, where sound is constructed from microscopic sonic ‘grains’, to extended works whose duration is measured not in minutes and seconds, but years.</p>
      <p>Bringing together ideas and theories of the engineer Denis Gabor and composers Iannis Xenakis and Curtis Roads, this episode examines early tape and computer music works using granular and pulsar synthesis. The show closes with a focus on two recent treatments of time in music: by the German artist Hanne Darboven and media producer Terre Thaemlitz.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess5_transcript_eng.0-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#5.1 Duration</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-5-1-duration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode explores the concept of duration in music. It examines the different ways that composers and musicians have explored duration in terms of both the large and small.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The fifth episode in the series continues to explore the idea of time in music practice, particularly in relation to duration.</p>
      <p>The show looks at how music is measured in terms of both micro and macroscopic intervals: through granular synthesis, where sound is constructed from microscopic sonic ‘grains’, to extended works whose duration is measured not in minutes and seconds, but years.</p><p>Bringing together ideas and theories of the engineer Denis Gabor and composers Iannis Xenakis and Curtis Roads, this episode examines early tape and computer music works using granular and pulsar synthesis.</p>
      <p>The show closes with a focus on two recent treatments of time in music: by the German artist Hanne Darboven and media producer Terre Thaemlitz.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_05_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#4.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-4-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #4.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The fourth episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC introduces the idea of time and its relationship to musical practices. The show opens with thoughts about time drawn from philosophy, science and musicology and shows how these are expressed in musical form, and looks at the origins of sonic action, musical behaviors and notational systems as a way of engaging with the temporal realm.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess4_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#4.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-4-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by Laurie Spiegel and Terre Thaemlitz</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>Each episode of this series is followed by a special accompanying programme of exclusive music by leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two works, the first by American composer Laurie Spiegel, followed by an excerpt of the soundtrack of a theatre play by Japanese composer Terre Thaemlitz.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_04_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#3.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-3-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #3.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The third episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC  examines the use of determinacy and indeterminacy in music. It looks at how chance has been used in a variety of ways in the composition and performance of musical works – from works derived from the tossing of coins, to more rigorous explorations of the laws governing probability. The programme also looks at the use of chance in the visual arts and literature, and changing approaches to science during the twentieth century, describing the impact of these disciplines upon music making.</p>
      <p>It investigates concepts and ideas behind these works with reference to works drawn from different traditions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess3_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#4.1 Time</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-4-1-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>The relationship between time and music and the impact of technological development and how time is treated within a range of musical idioms.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The fourth episode in this series introduces the idea of time and its relationship to musical practices.</p>
      <p>The show opens with thoughts about time drawn from philosophy, science and musicology and shows how these are expressed in musical form, and looks at the origins of sonic action, musical behaviors and notational systems as a way of engaging with the temporal realm. With a specific reference to the emergence of sound recording technologies – both vinyl and tape – the show examines how new technologies have impacted musical vocabularies and changed the relationship between sound, time and music.</p>
      <p>It closes with a brief look at how computer based editing has extended this paradigm and opened the way for stochastic methods of sound generation</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_04_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#2.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-2-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #2.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The second episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC looks at the use of formal systems in the composition and performance of musical works. It explains the diversity of approaches to musical systems using a range of technologies and processes.</p>
      <p>The episode asks how we might distinguish systems based procedures in music to other musical activities, and makes reference to technological development and implementation, structural complexity, and relationships to other musical traditions. We compare three tape-based approaches to composition that explore sound as a temporal and spatial phenomenon and refer to theoretical positions offered by notable artists working in this field.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Composingwithprocess2_transcript_eng-3.pdf" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#1.1 Transcript</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-1-1-transcript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Transcript of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC #1.1., curated by Mark Fell and Joe Gilmore.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The first episode of COMPOSING WITH PROCESS: PERSPECTIVES ON GENERATIVE AND SYSTEMS MUSIC investigates how music can be generated using a wide range of techniques. These range from very simple procedural systems, such as Mika Vainio’s ‘Twin Bleebs’ which features two repeating events going in and out of phase, to David Tudor’s ‘Neural Synthesis No.9’ – a more complex electronic system which explores indeterminacy through the emulation of neural activity. The programme also looks at music which has been composed using formal geometric and mathematical rules, for example: Martin Neukom’s ‘Studie 18′ and Thomas Brinkmann’s ’27 Fibonacci Numbers in a Binary Chain’.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="" type="application/pdf" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#3.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-3-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by Yasunao Tone and Christophe Charles.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>Each episode of this series is followed by a special accompanying programme of exclusive music by leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two works, the first by Japanese media artist Yasunao Tone, followed by a new piece by French composer Christophe Charles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#3.1 Determinacy and Indeterminacy</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-3-1-determinacy-and-indeterminacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>This episode looks at how chance has been used in a variety of ways in the composition and performance of musical works.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The third episode in the series examines the use of determinacy and indeterminacy in music. It looks at how chance has been used in a variety of ways in the composition and performance of musical works – from works derived from the tossing of coins, to more rigorous explorations of the laws governing probability. The programme also looks at the use of chance in the visual arts and literature, and changing approaches to science during the twentieth century, describing the impact of these disciplines upon music making.</p>
      <p>It investigates concepts and ideas behind these works with reference to works drawn from different traditions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_03_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#2.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-2-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by Marcus Schmickler and EVOL.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>Each episode of this series is followed by a special accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in the field. This show presents two contrasting generative works by German composer Marcus Schmickler and Catalan collective EVOL.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_02_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#2.1 Systems</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-2-1-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>The role of formalised systems in music making.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>The second episode in the series looks at the use of formal systems in the composition and performance of musical works. It explains the diversity of approaches to musical systems using a range of technologies and processes.</p>
      <p>The episode asks how we might distinguish systems based procedures in music to other musical activities, and makes reference to technological development and implementation, structural complexity, and relationships to other musical traditions.</p>
      <p>We compare three tape-based approaches to composition that explore sound as a temporal and spatial phenomenon and refer to theoretical positions offered by notable artists working in this field.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_02_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#1.2 Exclusives</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-1-2-exclusives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>Exclusive music by German artist Florian Hecker and Japanese artist Ryoji Ikeda.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>Each episode of this series is followed by a accompaniment programme of exclusive music by some of the leading sound artists and composers working in generative music. The first one presents two contrasting generative works by German artist Florian Hecker and Japanese artist Ryoji Ikeda.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_01_02_exclusives-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>#1.1 Continue</title>
      <link>https://rwm.macba.cat/en/podcasts/composing-with-process-perspectives-on-generative-and-systems-music-1-1-continue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description>A range of sound works representing different periods, traditions and approaches to generative and systems based music.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[[<p>‘Continue’ investigates how music can be generated using a wide range of techniques. These range from very simple procedural systems, such as Mika Vainio’s ‘Twin Bleebs’ which features two repeating events going in and out of phase, to David Tudor’s ‘Neural Synthesis No.9’ – a more complex electronic system which explores indeterminacy through the emulation of neural activity.</p>
      <p>The programme also looks at music which has been composed using formal geometric and mathematical rules, for example: Martin Neukom’s ‘Studie 18′ and Thomas Brinkmann’s ’27 Fibonacci Numbers in a Binary Chain’.</p>]]></content:encoded>
      <enclosure url="https://img.macba.cat/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/cwp_01_01-3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
